<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Ansari Blueprints</title>
 <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/"/>
 <updated>2017-12-23T20:01:07+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Quiz Night</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary---in-a-nutshell-what-did-you-do&quot;&gt;Summary - In a nutshell, what did you do.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unprecedented amounts of fun, combined with banter, education and forming the
bonds of brotherhood and sisterhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People got to meet new friends on their teams in the quiz and have a laugh while
hotly debating which of the answers to the questions seemed most correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food was provided afterwards and all round it was a good laugh. We slipped in a
couple of the ambiguous answers to the quiz to get a bit of controversy going,
keeping people engaged and fired up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-benefitsgoodness--what-was-good-&quot;&gt;1. Benefits/Goodness ( What was good )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We organised the quiz during freshers week (first week) at our university to
provide a casual alternative to most of the college organised events that would
have involved alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quiz was open to all and so was easy for people of any degrees of faith to
attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People got to bond with their team mates throughout the night and left better
friends than when they arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eager new students got to flex their intellectual acumen and see who had the best
general knowledge. We intentionally made the quiz was multiple-choice so that it
would be more engaging for people who didn’t know the answers and they could
discuss the plausibility of the different options among their team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provided a relaxed atmosphere where people could snack on free food and at the
end of the evening we had pizza for everyone and people broke out of their teams
to mingle with everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-step-by-step--what-did-you-guys-do-&quot;&gt;2. Step-by-step ( What did you guys do )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-setup&quot;&gt;Pre-setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Book out a room with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A projector for showing the quiz, multiple choice answers and pictures on screen.
pictures are important as a picture round is good fun!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Chairs, and ideally tables, that can be arranged into teams of four-six. These
can’t be too close to each other as otherwise people will overhear and can listen
to other teams. A couple of metres between each team is fine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A lectern from which the quizmaster could present the quiz.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write a quiz!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A multiple choice quiz is good because&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-challenges--potential-sticking-pounts--what-was-hard-&quot;&gt;3. Challenges &amp;amp; potential sticking pounts ( What was hard )&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did you find hard, how did you solve it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-logistical-tips-tips-for-others-&quot;&gt;4. Logistical tips (Tips for others )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-further-improvements-how-would-you-want-to-improve-the-event-if-you-had-more-resources&quot;&gt;5. Further improvements (How would you want to improve the event if you had more resources.)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ending-notes--closing-remarks-thoughts-well-wishes-and-advice-&quot;&gt;Ending notes ( Closing remarks, thoughts, well wishes and advice. )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A couple of the committee came up with questions before hand and put them into a nice powerpoint presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 sections, multiple choice to make it easier for people to at least have a guess and not just feel lost all evening.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;1 section on Islam but we didn’t want to isolate people who are less learned so we made the questions relatively easy and also limited it to only 1 round out of the 4.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So that we could project the quiz, (including picture rounds) while the quiz master presented from the lectern at the front.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The tables were useful so people could write down the quiz, eat pizza and serve themselves snacks and drinks easily. But also provided a clear demarcation of teams that helped team unity, team spirit and stopped people swapping teams half way through.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free pizza, snacks, soft-drinks, halal sweets (halalibos), crisps, cakes and cookies. Always good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Poetry Night</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-education/poetry-night/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-education/poetry-night</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An extremely successful event each time it has been run, 2013 and 2015. In 2015 the event was packed out with some people having to stand at the back. Over 100 people were able to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invite Islamic poets from London and around the country to come and perform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have an hour or two of performers and then an open-mic section where anyone is free to come and perform. Agree with a few people beforehand that they’ll prepare something for the open mic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charge tickets for entry to make a profit for ISoc but also to cover the costs of paying the artists to come and perform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Provide food as it’s a long evening event.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It might be nice to also roll out some rugs at the front and have people sit on the floor, this was tried in 2015 but no one sat on the rugs. It looked nice tho.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Open Jummuah</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-outreach/open-jummuah/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-outreach/open-jummuah</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Print out some informational booklets. Namely a “how to pray guide” so that guests understand what is going on when everyone else is performing salaat.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the ISoc is doing 2 jummuahs that week, best to only make one of them the open jummuah and really focus on that jummuah being catered to non-muslims and explaining Islamic terms that might otherwise be incomprehensible. This also means there is a larger group of non-muslims that attend and people will see that there is genuine interest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Normally combined with a bake sale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick a good khateeb and a relevant topic for him to speak about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mocktails Night</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Book a room (preferably with kitchens/bars)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get misc fun things from poundland/celebrations to jazz up the room (preferably with a theme - streamers, balloons, fairy lights)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy food from tesco: drinks, chips and dips, nice cupcakes, sweets, chocolate (this is better in bulk from poundland), fruit (make sure you have cocktail sticks) - should come to about £30&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice plates and glasses are all in the prayer room from previous times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get there about 1 hour early to set up the room (take scissors, tape and a knife)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have serving dishes/plates for the table&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers (and preferably spotify/other decent playlist)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sugar syrup for mocktails in advance (granulated sugar + water)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Halal Crawl</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We set a central meeting point in town that is convenient for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decide on a route around town that stops at as many halal places as feasibly possible along the way iA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important: Post a schedule beforehand and post updates to facebook as you go along so that people can meet you along the way iA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked really well and people were able to join us for certain parts depending on their schedule. Without this organisation only a handful of people show up at the beginning and leave slowly, the event would be poor.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Graduate Roundtables</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Educate ourselves about topics we casually hear about in the media by learning them from the people who actually work on them in daily basis (e.g. quantum physics from Physics students, cyber security from Computer Science students, theory of evolution from Biology/Medicine students, etc)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by refreshments and networking sessions&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Games Night</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A generally well received alternative to brothers football.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initially this ran at the same time as football but many brothers wanted to come to both games night and football.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a TV Room - Saturdays - 8 till l8.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xbox, Table tennis, kebabs and board games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Book out the DVD room to play Xbox.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Table tennis room to play ping pong.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Normally brothers will buy dinner at some point, either local kebabs or order in Pizza&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Much banter and good chat ensues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board games are always an option, yet to be tried though i believe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Formal Hall</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We used to hold this fortnightly, such that we’d aim to do three or four a term.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organise by getting someone at a given college to contact their hall manager and book in for a group of 20 or so. Or if you have several members at a particular college get each of them to book in several guests.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exeter provided us halal meat and we booked through the hall manager.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some college provide us with vegetarian food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For booking we had 5 of our members each book for 5 guests giving us 25 spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Demand is normally so high you can raise the price above cost price and raise some money for the ISoc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Segregation sometimes comes up as a point of contention. Our particular stance was to not enforce anything. Those who wanted to sit with just the same gender did so, those who wanted to mix did so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fast-a-thon</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/outreach/fast-a-thon/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/outreach/fast-a-thon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We invite non Muslims to fast one day with the MSA (usually during ashura)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we have a free dinner for anyone that wants to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the dinner, we also usually have a speaker and some kind of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fajr Breakfast</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;-Meet in the prayer room for fajr.
-Tell people to meet at 7, wait until 7:10 for late comers.
-Keep people updated on facebook as to where you go for breakfast. That way if they don’t make fajr in the prayer room they can still join for breakfast iA
-Then go to someone’s kitchen nearby and cook breakfast, eat and be merry. Either goto the supermarket the night before or wait for the morning and buy food once you see how many people come for fajr. (Need to check opening hours of shops before hand)
-Or eat at a nearby cafe that is open at that time. (Need to check opening hours beforehand)
-Or eat in hall at a nearby cafe’s breakfast. (opening times permitting)
-If fajr is early, spend time waiting for shops/cafes to open, either do work, zhikr, read Quran, chat, clean the store-cupboard, be merry etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cultural Fair</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/outreach/cultural-fair/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/outreach/cultural-fair</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Done annually to celebrate the different cultures embraced by Islam.
-Get a large room - Town hall or the chaplaincy have been used before.
-Each society or representative of a certain culture/nationality has a stall and they display some information, trinkets, books and food etc representative of their culture. Mostly food though.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Charity Dinner</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/charity/charity-dinner/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/charity/charity-dinner</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Booked into a relatively cheap formal hall for 20 people. Charged a markup on the cost price. Donated the profit to charity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Booked a restaurant or college at agreed price before hand per head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sold tickets at a marked up price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a fun ISoc member to host a nice auction. Where pieces of artwork or other items
were auctioned off.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bike Tour</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/bike-tour/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/bike-tour</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pick a time, destination and place to meet, then cycle away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has been done before by the brothers, normally early morning, perhaps after fajr and then back in time for a nice big brunch.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bake Sale</title>
   <link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/charity/Bake-Sale/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/charity/Bake-Sale</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mashallah always really popular, set up a table outside the prayer room in the foyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sell cake after jummah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the society donate cake, or can buy from Tesco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to get permission to sell cakes on site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also need to get permissions to setup a stand in the foyer (or wherever you are selling from).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
