<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-29T23:14:10+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/</id><title type="html">Ansari Blueprints</title><subtitle>The blueprints to build your community</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Quiz Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quiz Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Booked out the Doctrow hall in St Edmunds Hall&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A couple of the committee came up with questions before hand and put them into a nice powerpoint presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 sections, multiple choice to make it easier for people to at least have a guess and not just feel lost all evening.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 section on Islam but we didn’t want to isolate people who are less learned so we made the questions relatively easy and also limited it to only 1 round out of the 4.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free pizza, snacks, soft-drinks, crisps, cakes and cookies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">Booked out the Doctrow hall in St Edmunds Hall A couple of the committee came up with questions before hand and put them into a nice powerpoint presentation. 4 sections, multiple choice to make it easier for people to at least have a guess and not just feel lost all evening. 1 section on Islam but we didn’t want to isolate people who are less learned so we made the questions relatively easy and also limited it to only 1 round out of the 4. Free pizza, snacks, soft-drinks, crisps, cakes and cookies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poetry Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-education/poetry-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poetry Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-education/poetry-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-education/poetry-night/">&lt;p&gt;An extremely successful event each time it has been run, 2013 and 2015. In 2015 the event was packed out with some people having to stand at the back. Over 100 people were able to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invite Islamic poets from London and around the country to come and perform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have an hour or two of performers and then an open-mic section where anyone is free to come and perform. Agree with a few people beforehand that they’ll prepare something for the open mic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charge tickets for entry to make a profit for ISoc but also to cover the costs of paying the artists to come and perform.
-Provide food as it’s a long evening event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-It might be nice to also roll out some rugs at the front and have people sit on the floor, this was tried in 2015 but no one sat on the rugs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Islamic-education" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="arts," /><category term="socials" /><summary type="html">An extremely successful event each time it has been run, 2013 and 2015. In 2015 the event was packed out with some people having to stand at the back. Over 100 people were able to attend. Invite Islamic poets from London and around the country to come and perform. Have an hour or two of performers and then an open-mic section where anyone is free to come and perform. Agree with a few people beforehand that they’ll prepare something for the open mic. Charge tickets for entry to make a profit for ISoc but also to cover the costs of paying the artists to come and perform. -Provide food as it’s a long evening event. -It might be nice to also roll out some rugs at the front and have people sit on the floor, this was tried in 2015 but no one sat on the rugs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Jummuah</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-outreach/open-jummuah/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Jummuah" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-outreach/open-jummuah</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/islamic-outreach/open-jummuah/">&lt;p&gt;-Print out some informational booklets for non-muslims. Namely a “how to pray guide” so that they understand what is going on when everyone else is actually performing salaat.
-If the ISoc is doing 2 jummuahs that week, best to only make one of them the open jummuah and really focus on that jummuah being catered to non-muslims. This also means there is a larger group of non-muslims that attend and people will see that there is genuine interest.
-Normally combined with a bake sale.
-Pick a good khateeb and a good topic for him to speak about.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Islamic-outreach" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="outreach," /><category term="dawaah," /><category term="interfaith" /><summary type="html">-Print out some informational booklets for non-muslims. Namely a “how to pray guide” so that they understand what is going on when everyone else is actually performing salaat. -If the ISoc is doing 2 jummuahs that week, best to only make one of them the open jummuah and really focus on that jummuah being catered to non-muslims. This also means there is a larger group of non-muslims that attend and people will see that there is genuine interest. -Normally combined with a bake sale. -Pick a good khateeb and a good topic for him to speak about.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mocktails Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mocktails Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night/">&lt;p&gt;Book a room (preferably with kitchens/bars)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get misc fun things from poundland/celebrations to jazz up the room (preferably with a theme - streamers, balloons, fairy lights)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy food from tesco: drinks, chips and dips, nice cupcakes, sweets, chocolate (this is better in bulk from poundland), fruit (make sure you have cocktail sticks) - should come to about £30&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice plates and glasses are all in the prayer room from previous times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get there about 1 hour early to set up the room (take scissors, tape and a knife)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have serving dishes/plates for the table&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers (and preferably spotify/other decent playlist)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sugar syrup for mocktails in advance (granulated sugar + water)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">Book a room (preferably with kitchens/bars) Get misc fun things from poundland/celebrations to jazz up the room (preferably with a theme - streamers, balloons, fairy lights) Buy food from tesco: drinks, chips and dips, nice cupcakes, sweets, chocolate (this is better in bulk from poundland), fruit (make sure you have cocktail sticks) - should come to about £30 Nice plates and glasses are all in the prayer room from previous times Get there about 1 hour early to set up the room (take scissors, tape and a knife) Make sure you have serving dishes/plates for the table Speakers (and preferably spotify/other decent playlist) Make sugar syrup for mocktails in advance (granulated sugar + water)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Halal Crawl</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Halal Crawl" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl/">&lt;p&gt;Start at Jericho
Walk to Cowley
Eat at as many halal places as feasibly possible along the way iA.
Important: Post a schedule beforehand and post updates to facebook as you go along so that people can meet you along the way iA. This worked really well and people were able to join us for certain parts depending on their schedule.
-Without the organisation only a handful of people show up at the beginning and leave slowly, the event would be poor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">Start at Jericho Walk to Cowley Eat at as many halal places as feasibly possible along the way iA. Important: Post a schedule beforehand and post updates to facebook as you go along so that people can meet you along the way iA. This worked really well and people were able to join us for certain parts depending on their schedule. -Without the organisation only a handful of people show up at the beginning and leave slowly, the event would be poor.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Graduate Roundtables</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graduate Roundtables" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable/">&lt;p&gt;Educate ourselves about (sometimes controversial) topics we casually hear about in the media by learning them from the people who actually work on them in daily basis (e.g. quantum physics from Physics students, cyber security from Computer Science students, theory of evolution from Biology/Medicine students, etc)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by refreshments and networking sessions&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">Educate ourselves about (sometimes controversial) topics we casually hear about in the media by learning them from the people who actually work on them in daily basis (e.g. quantum physics from Physics students, cyber security from Computer Science students, theory of evolution from Biology/Medicine students, etc) Followed by refreshments and networking sessions</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Games Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Games Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night/">&lt;p&gt;-A generally well received alternative to brothers football.
-Initially this ran at the same time as football but many brothers wanted to come to both games night and football.
-Find a TV Room - Saturdays - 8 till l8.
-Xbox, Table tennis, kebabs and board games.
-Book out the DVD room to play Xbox.
-Table tennis room to play ping pong.
-Normally brothers will buy dinner at some point, either local kebabs or order in Pizza
-Much banter and good chat ensues.
-Board games are always an option, yet to be tried though i believe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">-A generally well received alternative to brothers football. -Initially this ran at the same time as football but many brothers wanted to come to both games night and football. -Find a TV Room - Saturdays - 8 till l8. -Xbox, Table tennis, kebabs and board games. -Book out the DVD room to play Xbox. -Table tennis room to play ping pong. -Normally brothers will buy dinner at some point, either local kebabs or order in Pizza -Much banter and good chat ensues. -Board games are always an option, yet to be tried though i believe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Formal Hall</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Formal Hall" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall/">&lt;p&gt;-We used to hold this fortnightly, such that we’d aim to do three or four a term.
-Organise by getting someone at a given college to contact their hall manager and book in for a group of 20 or so. Or if you have several members at a particular college get each of them to book in several guests.
-Exeter provided us halal meat and we booked through the hall manager.
-St Johns provided us with vegetarian food and we had 5 of our members each book for 5 guests giving us 25 spaces.
-Demand is normally so high you can raise the price above cost price and raise some money for the ISoc.
-Segregation is sometimes a point of contention. Our particular stance was to not enforce anything. Those who wanted to sit with just the same gender did so, those who wanted to mix  did so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials" /><summary type="html">-We used to hold this fortnightly, such that we’d aim to do three or four a term. -Organise by getting someone at a given college to contact their hall manager and book in for a group of 20 or so. Or if you have several members at a particular college get each of them to book in several guests. -Exeter provided us halal meat and we booked through the hall manager. -St Johns provided us with vegetarian food and we had 5 of our members each book for 5 guests giving us 25 spaces. -Demand is normally so high you can raise the price above cost price and raise some money for the ISoc. -Segregation is sometimes a point of contention. Our particular stance was to not enforce anything. Those who wanted to sit with just the same gender did so, those who wanted to mix did so.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fast-a-thon</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/outreach/fast-a-thon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fast-a-thon" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/outreach/fast-a-thon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/outreach/fast-a-thon/">&lt;p&gt;We invite non Muslims to fast one day with the MSA (usually during ashura)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we have a free dinner for anyone that wants to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the dinner, we also usually have a speaker and some kind of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ziad Maqbool</name></author><category term="Outreach" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="fasting," /><category term="dawaah," /><category term="interfaith," /><category term="outreach" /><summary type="html">We invite non Muslims to fast one day with the MSA (usually during ashura) Then we have a free dinner for anyone that wants to attend. At the dinner, we also usually have a speaker and some kind of entertainment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fajr Breakfast</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fajr Breakfast" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast/">&lt;p&gt;-Meet in the prayer room for fajr.
-Tell people to meet at 7, wait until 7:10 for late comers.
-Keep people updated on facebook as to where you go for breakfast. That way if they don’t make fajr in the prayer room they can still join for breakfast iA
-Then go to a nearby college and cook breakfast, eat and be merry. Either goto the supermarket the night before or wait for the morning and buy food once you see how many people come for fajr. (Need to check opening hours of shops before hand)
-Or eat at a nearby cafe that is open at that time. (Need to check opening hours beforehand)
-Or eat in hall at a nearby college’s breakfast. (opening times permitting)
-If fajr is early, spend time waiting for shops/cafes to open, either do work, zhikr, read Quran, chat, clean the store-cupboard, be merry etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="food," /><category term="breakfast," /><category term="brunch," /><category term="cooking," /><category term="fajr," /><category term="prayer," /><summary type="html">-Meet in the prayer room for fajr. -Tell people to meet at 7, wait until 7:10 for late comers. -Keep people updated on facebook as to where you go for breakfast. That way if they don’t make fajr in the prayer room they can still join for breakfast iA -Then go to a nearby college and cook breakfast, eat and be merry. Either goto the supermarket the night before or wait for the morning and buy food once you see how many people come for fajr. (Need to check opening hours of shops before hand) -Or eat at a nearby cafe that is open at that time. (Need to check opening hours beforehand) -Or eat in hall at a nearby college’s breakfast. (opening times permitting) -If fajr is early, spend time waiting for shops/cafes to open, either do work, zhikr, read Quran, chat, clean the store-cupboard, be merry etc.</summary></entry></feed>