<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-25T15:45:52+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/</id><title type="html">Ansari Blueprints</title><subtitle>The blueprints to build your community</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Poetry Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/spirituality/poetry-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poetry Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/spirituality/poetry-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/spirituality/poetry-night/">&lt;p&gt;An extremely successful event each time it has been run, 2013 and 2015. In 2015 the event was packed out with some people having to stand at the back. Over 100 people were able to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invite Islamic poets from London and around the country to come and perform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have an hour or two of performers and then an open-mic section where anyone is free to come and perform. Agree with a few people beforehand that they’ll prepare something for the open mic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charge tickets for entry to make a profit for ISoc but also to cover the costs of paying the artists to come and perform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Provide food as it’s a long evening event.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It might be nice to also roll out some rugs at the front and have people sit on the floor, this was tried in 2015 but no one sat on the rugs. It looked nice tho.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Spirituality" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="arts," /><category term="socials" /><summary type="html">An extremely successful event each time it has been run, 2013 and 2015. In 2015 the event was packed out with some people having to stand at the back. Over 100 people were able to attend. Invite Islamic poets from London and around the country to come and perform. Have an hour or two of performers and then an open-mic section where anyone is free to come and perform. Agree with a few people beforehand that they’ll prepare something for the open mic. Charge tickets for entry to make a profit for ISoc but also to cover the costs of paying the artists to come and perform. Provide food as it’s a long evening event. It might be nice to also roll out some rugs at the front and have people sit on the floor, this was tried in 2015 but no one sat on the rugs. It looked nice tho.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quiz Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quiz Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/quiz-night/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary---in-a-nutshell-what-did-you-do&quot;&gt;Summary - In a nutshell, what did you do.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unprecedented amounts of fun, combined with banter, education and forming the
bonds of brotherhood and sisterhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People got to meet new friends on their teams in the quiz and have a laugh while
hotly debating which of the answers to the questions seemed most correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food was provided afterwards and all round it was a good laugh. We slipped in a
couple of the ambiguous answers to the quiz to get a bit of controversy going,
keeping people engaged and fired up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-benefitsgoodness--what-was-good-&quot;&gt;1. Benefits/Goodness ( What was good )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We organised the quiz during freshers week (first week) at our university to
provide a casual alternative to most of the college organised events that would
have involved alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quiz was open to all and we wrote the questions such that it would be
easy for people of any degrees of faith to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People got to bond with their team mates throughout the night and left better
friends than when they arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eager new students got to flex their intellectual acumen and see who had the best
general knowledge. We intentionally made sure the quiz was multiple-choice so that
it would be more engaging for people who didn’t know the answers; as they could
discuss the plausibility of the different options among their team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provided a relaxed atmosphere where people could snack on free food and at the
end of the evening we had pizza for everyone as people broke out of their teams
to mingle with the other quizees!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-step-by-step--what-did-you-guys-do-&quot;&gt;2. Step-by-step ( What did you guys do )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-setup&quot;&gt;Pre-setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Book out a room with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A projector for showing the quiz, multiple choice answers and pictures on screen.
pictures are important as a picture round is good fun!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Chairs, and ideally tables, that can be arranged into teams of four-six. These
can’t be too close to each other as otherwise people will overhear and can listen
to other teams. A couple of metres between each team is fine. Leave one table free
for snacks and food too!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A lectern from which the quizmaster can present the quiz.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write a quiz!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A multiple choice quiz is good as eveeyone can give it a go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick a fun quiz quiz master!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone who can make a few jokes and keep the room feeling a bit lively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We didn’t tell the quiz master the answers, this made him a better host as he
was able to sincerely joke about some of the questions say things like (Wow, that’s
a hard one).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organise Food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide which pizza / catering you want for the night, and see if you can find
sponsorship.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a couple of people buy snacks beforehand. Ideally nibbles like cookies,
halal sweets (halalibos), crisps, cakes, fruit and soft drinks.We tried to buy
foods that were individually wrapped, like individually wrapped cakes, so that we could reuse them for our next event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invite people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the word out via text, email, social media, word of mouth, announcement
after jummuah, the whole lot! Get the Student Union to help you advertise to new
students and be sure to tell people about it at Freshers’ fair!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure someone has a laptop with the &lt;em&gt;right wire&lt;/em&gt; to plug into the projector,
we forgot this and someone had to cycle home to pick up an HDMI adapter! If the projector is already plugged into a computer, make sure you’ll have internet
access to get a copy of the quiz or you have a thumb drive with a copy of the
quiz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy a prize for the winning team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We bought a few small boxes of chocolate for each person on the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were hosting quite an academic crowd so we also bought some nice books
about Islam as prizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-night&quot;&gt;On the night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ushered people to the venue, making sure to have enough people waiting at
the entrance and guiding people through to the hall where we held it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a few people bring different snacks. One person delegated for snacks a few
people delegated to drinks as they’re heavier. Made sure to bring paper plates
and plastic cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a few people come early to help us set up the room, make sure the tables
were laid out so everyone could sit in teams of 5 and see the quiz-master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our quiz had several rounds. After each round, teams swapped with the people
next to them and marked the quiz. Then we kept a scoreboard of which team was
ahead. Kept it a bit competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the last round we did pizza. People mingled and after a while we cleared
the venue, started to put the chairs away to tidy up and had a few volunteers
help us with cleanup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-challenges--potential-sticking-points--what-was-hard-&quot;&gt;3. Challenges &amp;amp; potential sticking points ( What was hard )&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing the quiz was quite hard for us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to get a group of us to sit down and try to come up with the questions
that weren’t going to be too hard or too easy for our audience. We didn’t want
any team to be able to get everything right, but also we didn’t want there to be
teams that got close to nothing right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made sure the questions were on different themes and came from different
people. We had different rounds, and in future years we changed some rounds,
these were rounds like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General Knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Islam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Islamic history&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Islam and modernity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Picture round&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Famous mosques&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anything!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our other main challenge was logistics on the night. We forgot to bring an
adapter for plugging a laptop into the projector. We also had to signpost the
venue properly so it was easy for people to find. Pizza was late, which we could
have fixed by ordering earlier and specifying a delivery time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-logistical-tips-tips-for-others-&quot;&gt;4. Logistical tips (Tips for others )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quiz takes a surprisingly long time to write!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 1 section on Islam but we didn’t want to isolate people who were less
learned so we made the questions relatively easy and limited religion to 1 round
out of the 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure the venue is easy to find for new people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Order food so it comes in good time and make sure you have a few designated
people beforehand to get snacks and set them up. As well as some people to hang
around and clean things up afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-further-improvements-how-would-you-want-to-improve-the-event-if-you-had-more-resources&quot;&gt;5. Further improvements (How would you want to improve the event if you had more resources.)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our quiz was quite basic, could have had nicer design on the slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a larger budget and more volunteers could have served nicer food than just
pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a larger budget could have bought a bigger prize for the winners and
smaller prices for the runners up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ending-notes--closing-remarks-thoughts-well-wishes-and-advice-&quot;&gt;Ending notes ( Closing remarks, thoughts, well wishes and advice. )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alhumdulillah What initially we thought would be a relatively quiet event ended
up being a really lively evening of fun, banter, competition, learning and good
food! An unprecedented success that our ISoc went on to host again in future
years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">Summary - In a nutshell, what did you do. Unprecedented amounts of fun, combined with banter, education and forming the bonds of brotherhood and sisterhood. People got to meet new friends on their teams in the quiz and have a laugh while hotly debating which of the answers to the questions seemed most correct. Food was provided afterwards and all round it was a good laugh. We slipped in a couple of the ambiguous answers to the quiz to get a bit of controversy going, keeping people engaged and fired up. 1. Benefits/Goodness ( What was good ) We organised the quiz during freshers week (first week) at our university to provide a casual alternative to most of the college organised events that would have involved alcohol. The quiz was open to all and we wrote the questions such that it would be easy for people of any degrees of faith to attend. People got to bond with their team mates throughout the night and left better friends than when they arrived. Eager new students got to flex their intellectual acumen and see who had the best general knowledge. We intentionally made sure the quiz was multiple-choice so that it would be more engaging for people who didn’t know the answers; as they could discuss the plausibility of the different options among their team. We provided a relaxed atmosphere where people could snack on free food and at the end of the evening we had pizza for everyone as people broke out of their teams to mingle with the other quizees! 2. Step-by-step ( What did you guys do ) Pre-setup Book out a room with: A projector for showing the quiz, multiple choice answers and pictures on screen. pictures are important as a picture round is good fun! Chairs, and ideally tables, that can be arranged into teams of four-six. These can’t be too close to each other as otherwise people will overhear and can listen to other teams. A couple of metres between each team is fine. Leave one table free for snacks and food too! A lectern from which the quizmaster can present the quiz. Write a quiz! A multiple choice quiz is good as eveeyone can give it a go Pick a fun quiz quiz master! Someone who can make a few jokes and keep the room feeling a bit lively. We didn’t tell the quiz master the answers, this made him a better host as he was able to sincerely joke about some of the questions say things like (Wow, that’s a hard one). Organise Food Decide which pizza / catering you want for the night, and see if you can find sponsorship. Have a couple of people buy snacks beforehand. Ideally nibbles like cookies, halal sweets (halalibos), crisps, cakes, fruit and soft drinks.We tried to buy foods that were individually wrapped, like individually wrapped cakes, so that we could reuse them for our next event. Invite people! Get the word out via text, email, social media, word of mouth, announcement after jummuah, the whole lot! Get the Student Union to help you advertise to new students and be sure to tell people about it at Freshers’ fair! Make sure someone has a laptop with the right wire to plug into the projector, we forgot this and someone had to cycle home to pick up an HDMI adapter! If the projector is already plugged into a computer, make sure you’ll have internet access to get a copy of the quiz or you have a thumb drive with a copy of the quiz. Buy a prize for the winning team! We bought a few small boxes of chocolate for each person on the team. We were hosting quite an academic crowd so we also bought some nice books about Islam as prizes. On the night We ushered people to the venue, making sure to have enough people waiting at the entrance and guiding people through to the hall where we held it. We had a few people bring different snacks. One person delegated for snacks a few people delegated to drinks as they’re heavier. Made sure to bring paper plates and plastic cups. We had a few people come early to help us set up the room, make sure the tables were laid out so everyone could sit in teams of 5 and see the quiz-master. Our quiz had several rounds. After each round, teams swapped with the people next to them and marked the quiz. Then we kept a scoreboard of which team was ahead. Kept it a bit competitive. After the last round we did pizza. People mingled and after a while we cleared the venue, started to put the chairs away to tidy up and had a few volunteers help us with cleanup. 3. Challenges &amp;amp; potential sticking points ( What was hard ) Writing the quiz was quite hard for us! We had to get a group of us to sit down and try to come up with the questions that weren’t going to be too hard or too easy for our audience. We didn’t want any team to be able to get everything right, but also we didn’t want there to be teams that got close to nothing right. We made sure the questions were on different themes and came from different people. We had different rounds, and in future years we changed some rounds, these were rounds like: General Knowledge Islam Islamic history Islam and modernity Picture round Famous mosques Anything! Our other main challenge was logistics on the night. We forgot to bring an adapter for plugging a laptop into the projector. We also had to signpost the venue properly so it was easy for people to find. Pizza was late, which we could have fixed by ordering earlier and specifying a delivery time! 4. Logistical tips (Tips for others ) The quiz takes a surprisingly long time to write! We had 1 section on Islam but we didn’t want to isolate people who were less learned so we made the questions relatively easy and limited religion to 1 round out of the 4. Make sure the venue is easy to find for new people. Order food so it comes in good time and make sure you have a few designated people beforehand to get snacks and set them up. As well as some people to hang around and clean things up afterwards. 5. Further improvements (How would you want to improve the event if you had more resources.) Our quiz was quite basic, could have had nicer design on the slides. With a larger budget and more volunteers could have served nicer food than just pizza. With a larger budget could have bought a bigger prize for the winners and smaller prices for the runners up. Ending notes ( Closing remarks, thoughts, well wishes and advice. ) Alhumdulillah What initially we thought would be a relatively quiet event ended up being a really lively evening of fun, banter, competition, learning and good food! An unprecedented success that our ISoc went on to host again in future years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mocktails Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mocktails Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/mocktails-night/">&lt;p&gt;Book a room (preferably with kitchens/bars)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get misc fun things from poundland/celebrations to jazz up the room (preferably with a theme - streamers, balloons, fairy lights)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy food from tesco: drinks, chips and dips, nice cupcakes, sweets, chocolate (this is better in bulk from poundland), fruit (make sure you have cocktail sticks) - should come to about £30&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice plates and glasses are all in the prayer room from previous times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get there about 1 hour early to set up the room (take scissors, tape and a knife)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have serving dishes/plates for the table&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers (and preferably spotify/other decent playlist)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sugar syrup for mocktails in advance (granulated sugar + water)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">Book a room (preferably with kitchens/bars) Get misc fun things from poundland/celebrations to jazz up the room (preferably with a theme - streamers, balloons, fairy lights) Buy food from tesco: drinks, chips and dips, nice cupcakes, sweets, chocolate (this is better in bulk from poundland), fruit (make sure you have cocktail sticks) - should come to about £30 Nice plates and glasses are all in the prayer room from previous times Get there about 1 hour early to set up the room (take scissors, tape and a knife) Make sure you have serving dishes/plates for the table Speakers (and preferably spotify/other decent playlist) Make sugar syrup for mocktails in advance (granulated sugar + water)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Halal Crawl</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Halal Crawl" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/halal-crawl/">&lt;p&gt;We set a central meeting point in town that is convenient for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decide on a route around town that stops at as many halal places as feasibly possible along the way iA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important: Post a schedule beforehand and post updates to facebook as you go along so that people can meet you along the way iA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked really well and people were able to join us for certain parts depending on their schedule. Without this organisation only a handful of people show up at the beginning and leave slowly, the event would be poor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">We set a central meeting point in town that is convenient for everyone. Decide on a route around town that stops at as many halal places as feasibly possible along the way iA. Important: Post a schedule beforehand and post updates to facebook as you go along so that people can meet you along the way iA. This worked really well and people were able to join us for certain parts depending on their schedule. Without this organisation only a handful of people show up at the beginning and leave slowly, the event would be poor.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Graduate Roundtables</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graduate Roundtables" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/graduate-roundtable/">&lt;p&gt;Educate ourselves about topics we casually hear about in the media by learning them from the people who actually work on them in daily basis (e.g. quantum physics from Physics students, cyber security from Computer Science students, theory of evolution from Biology/Medicine students, etc)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by refreshments and networking sessions&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">Educate ourselves about topics we casually hear about in the media by learning them from the people who actually work on them in daily basis (e.g. quantum physics from Physics students, cyber security from Computer Science students, theory of evolution from Biology/Medicine students, etc) Followed by refreshments and networking sessions</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Games Night</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Games Night" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/games-night/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A generally well received alternative to brothers football.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initially this ran at the same time as football but many brothers wanted to come to both games night and football.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a TV Room - Saturdays - 8 till l8.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xbox, Table tennis, kebabs and board games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Book out the DVD room to play Xbox.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Table tennis room to play ping pong.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Normally brothers will buy dinner at some point, either local kebabs or order in Pizza&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Much banter and good chat ensues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board games are always an option, yet to be tried though i believe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="sisters-socials" /><summary type="html">A generally well received alternative to brothers football. Initially this ran at the same time as football but many brothers wanted to come to both games night and football. Find a TV Room - Saturdays - 8 till l8. Xbox, Table tennis, kebabs and board games. Book out the DVD room to play Xbox. Table tennis room to play ping pong. Normally brothers will buy dinner at some point, either local kebabs or order in Pizza Much banter and good chat ensues. Board games are always an option, yet to be tried though i believe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Formal Hall</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Formal Hall" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/formal-hall/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We used to hold this fortnightly, such that we’d aim to do three or four a term.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organise by getting someone at a given college to contact their hall manager and book in for a group of 20 or so. Or if you have several members at a particular college get each of them to book in several guests.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exeter provided us halal meat and we booked through the hall manager.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some college provide us with vegetarian food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For booking we had 5 of our members each book for 5 guests giving us 25 spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Demand is normally so high you can raise the price above cost price and raise some money for the ISoc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Segregation sometimes comes up as a point of contention. Our particular stance was to not enforce anything. Those who wanted to sit with just the same gender did so, those who wanted to mix did so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials" /><summary type="html">We used to hold this fortnightly, such that we’d aim to do three or four a term. Organise by getting someone at a given college to contact their hall manager and book in for a group of 20 or so. Or if you have several members at a particular college get each of them to book in several guests. Exeter provided us halal meat and we booked through the hall manager. Some college provide us with vegetarian food. For booking we had 5 of our members each book for 5 guests giving us 25 spaces. Demand is normally so high you can raise the price above cost price and raise some money for the ISoc. Segregation sometimes comes up as a point of contention. Our particular stance was to not enforce anything. Those who wanted to sit with just the same gender did so, those who wanted to mix did so.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fajr Breakfast</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fajr Breakfast" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/fajr-breakfast/">&lt;p&gt;-Meet in the prayer room for fajr.
-Tell people to meet at 7, wait until 7:10 for late comers.
-Keep people updated on facebook as to where you go for breakfast. That way if they don’t make fajr in the prayer room they can still join for breakfast iA
-Then go to someone’s kitchen nearby and cook breakfast, eat and be merry. Either goto the supermarket the night before or wait for the morning and buy food once you see how many people come for fajr. (Need to check opening hours of shops before hand)
-Or eat at a nearby cafe that is open at that time. (Need to check opening hours beforehand)
-Or eat in hall at a nearby cafe’s breakfast. (opening times permitting)
-If fajr is early, spend time waiting for shops/cafes to open, either do work, zhikr, read Quran, chat, clean the store-cupboard, be merry etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="food," /><category term="breakfast," /><category term="brunch," /><category term="cooking," /><category term="fajr," /><category term="prayer," /><summary type="html">-Meet in the prayer room for fajr. -Tell people to meet at 7, wait until 7:10 for late comers. -Keep people updated on facebook as to where you go for breakfast. That way if they don’t make fajr in the prayer room they can still join for breakfast iA -Then go to someone’s kitchen nearby and cook breakfast, eat and be merry. Either goto the supermarket the night before or wait for the morning and buy food once you see how many people come for fajr. (Need to check opening hours of shops before hand) -Or eat at a nearby cafe that is open at that time. (Need to check opening hours beforehand) -Or eat in hall at a nearby cafe’s breakfast. (opening times permitting) -If fajr is early, spend time waiting for shops/cafes to open, either do work, zhikr, read Quran, chat, clean the store-cupboard, be merry etc.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bike Tour</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/bike-tour/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bike Tour" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/bike-tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/socials/bike-tour/">&lt;p&gt;Pick a time, destination and place to meet, then cycle away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has been done before by the brothers, normally early morning, perhaps after fajr and then back in time for a nice big brunch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ansari Blueprints</name></author><category term="Socials" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="socials," /><category term="outside," /><category term="outdoors," /><category term="exercise" /><summary type="html">Pick a time, destination and place to meet, then cycle away! Has been done before by the brothers, normally early morning, perhaps after fajr and then back in time for a nice big brunch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fast-a-thon</title><link href="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/local-community/fast-a-thon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fast-a-thon" /><published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.ansariblueprints.com/local-community/fast-a-thon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.ansariblueprints.com/local-community/fast-a-thon/">&lt;p&gt;We invite non Muslims to fast one day with the MSA (usually during ashura)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we have a free dinner for anyone that wants to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the dinner, we also usually have a speaker and some kind of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ziad Maqbool</name></author><category term="Local-Community" /><category term="ISoc," /><category term="MSA," /><category term="fasting," /><category term="dawaah," /><category term="interfaith," /><category term="outreach" /><summary type="html">We invite non Muslims to fast one day with the MSA (usually during ashura) Then we have a free dinner for anyone that wants to attend. At the dinner, we also usually have a speaker and some kind of entertainment.</summary></entry></feed>